Front-end focused full-stack developer with an eye for design and passion for a clean and simple user experience. I have experience in a large array of programming technologies and design principles, but my wheelhouse technologies are PHP, C#, ASP.Net MVC, Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap; while my software design focus is shifting to Service-Oriented Architecture (SoA) and Separation of Concerns (SoC) design principals. Currently, I spend the majority of my time working on updating troubled user interfaces, improving user experience, and streamlining user interaction and workflow on legacy, current, and next-gen web-based applications.

Education

BS Computer Science

Southeastern Louisiana University 2005 – 2010

Projects

IRIS https://iris.yorkrsg.com

Safety Library

Client customizable safety web portal & search engine that utilizes dynamic content morphing and integrated custom branding.

MySafetyPoint https://mysafetypoint.com/

An example of a privately branded IRIS portal built for Farmers Insurance. The IRIS app has served over 20 individual and custom branded clients over the past 8 years.

FOCUS Help Portal https://help.focus.yorkrsg.com/

Built as a companion to York's RIMS system, FOCUS Help Portal provide training material, and other useful information to help FOCUS users.

Email Signature Generator https://emailsig.yorkrsg.com/

Built with bootstrap v4 & PHP to help users create their email signatures at York.

Provider Gateway https://providergateway.yorkrsg.com/

Provider Gateway is a self-service tool to assist providers in looking up payment statuses from claims submitted through York

Data X Cheatsheet http://datax.yorkrsg.com

Another companion training product to the Claim Systems at York to provide

Experience

Web Architect York Risk Services Group

Jan 2014 - Present Mandeville, LA

Works with web technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Responsive Web Design, PHP (Laravel, Joomla, Wordpress), Javascript (AngularJS, jQuery, RivetsJS, MVVM), LAMP Stack/Administration, MySQL/MSSQL, MongoDB, Apache Solr, Task Runners (Grunt, Gulp, Yarn), ASP.Net Webforms/MVC/Entity Framework and processes such as user experience design (UXD) and user interface design (UID), web presence, web mastery.

Leads colleagues in best practices for Web design, Software Architecture, and Continuous Integration technologies.

Leading expert in configuration of Continuous Integration workflows to improve DevOps practices, working with TeamCity, Octopus Deploy, and Jenkins in both Linux and Windows environments.

Application Programmer / Analyst MEDTRON Software Intelligence Corporation

Apr 2013 - Dec 2013 Covington, LA

Works with leading edge web technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, PHP, Zend MVC, PDO DB Abstraction with Doctrine 2 ORM/DBAL.

Software Engineer II York Risk Services Group

Dec 2011 - Apr 2013 Mandeville, La

York acquires Avizent. Software Engineering and development continuation.

Software Engineer I Avizent Risk

Jun 2011 - Dec 2011

Avizent acquires FARA. Software Engineering and development continuation.

Applications Systems Analyst/Programmer FARA Insurance Services

Feb 2009 - Jun 2011

Progress 4GL - OpenEdge Advanced Business Language, or OpenEdge ABL for short, is a business application development language created and maintained by Progress Software Corporation (PSC).

Open Source - JavaScript, jQuery, jQueryUI, PHP, MySQL, Perl, XML, HTML, CSS. Server Configuration/Administration - SuSE Linux Enterprise, Apache 2.x, Apache Tomcat 5.x/6, Apache Solr, Apache Lucene, Secure FTP.

Adobe LiveCycle - Trained in Adobe LiveCycle ES2 Process Development, LiveCycle ES2 Server Configuration and Management, Adobe ES2 Form Design and Implementation.

insight into claim system actions on specific data elements.

Yoogle

Yoogle is a search engine for all things York. Given York's impressive growth, we have many systems that don't naturally talk to each other. Our staff has to work in a number of these systems and Yoogle indexes the information across many systems and puts it all in one searchable place. Web Services - Familiar with many web service protocols, including SOAP and REST endpoint configurations in Progress and Java environments.

Web Design (HCI) - Implementation of existing and new HCI (Human-Computer Interaction) interface design and development. Self-taught graphics design and implementation in web and desktop environments; including Progress SpeedScript, PHP, HTML, and JavaScript and JavaScript frameworks as well as using graphics design tools such as Adobe Fireworks, Illustrator, and Photoshop.

Technician Campo Better Living

May 2005 – Feb 2008 Greater New Orleans Area

Worked as a home theater installation technician doing mainly residential work, with some

commercial work. Residential work ranged from pre-wire to post-wire and troubleshooting

and repair of home theater systems, home automation systems, and home network systems

(low end to high end). Commercial work ranged from mostly flat panel television

installations and repair along with small and large sound systems. Also programming home

automation systems such as Russound and Control 4 whole house audio/video systems. As

well as installation and configuration of some residential and commercial security and

camera systems.

Clerk La-Z-Boy

Aug 2004 - May 2005

Skills

HTML5					
CSS3					
C#					
ASP.Net					
PHP					
jQuery					
Bootstrap					
JavaScript					
Linux					
LAMP					
Apache Solr					
MSSQL					
MySQL					
Entity Framework					
AngularJS					
RivetsJS					
Zend Framework					

MongoDB

